

DETAILS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarah-k-payne/

EDUCATION

Southern Methodist University Web Development Certificate 2017

University of Texas

BSc Nutrition in Dietetics Minor in Business 2009-2013

SKILLS

TS/JS Node.js React/Angular.js Redux React Native/Expo Apollo/GraphQL **REST** CI/CD Jest/Playwright MUI/Native Base/BootStrap SQL/NoSQL/Redis Azure Cloud Services HL7 Integrations Agile/Scrum Storybook

SARAH PAYNE

Senior Software Engineer

ABOUT ME

I'm a clinical dietitian turned software engineer with over six years of experience providing high-quality code on both the frontend and backend. I'm an effective cross-team collaborator with an eye for detail, a passion for good user experience, and a love of mentorship. I'm currently in the process of relocating back to Texas from Denmark with an estimated arrival date of September 19th.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Jun 2022 - Present

Lenus eHealth | Copenhagen, Denmark

Senior Software Engineer, Mission Lead

Software Engineer, Mission Lead

Fullstack development on web and mobile with TypeScript, Node.js, React, React Native, Expo, Apollo/GraphQL, PostgreSQL, i18n, and Jest. Provide mentorship and onboarding of student engineers. As a Team Mission Lead, I balance extra cross-team responsibilities including technical investigation and scoping of upcoming features, driving technical planning and delivery of current cycle work, creating and managing epics and stories, collaborating with other engineering teams on platform and DX improvements, and doing check-ins regularly with team members.

2021-2022

Baylor Scott & White Healthcare | Dallas, Texas (Remote)

Senior Software Engineer, Tech Lead

Software Engineer, Tech Lead

Fullstack development of the customer health portal in an Agile environment using Javascript, React, Redux, .NET Framework, .NET Core, MS SQL, and CosmosDB. Bootstrapped an internal portal for appointment scheduling within Microsoft Dynamics 365 in conjunction with the CRM department and Epic engineers. Created a documentation system for our monthly deployments and hotfixes now utilized by the entire web team for smooth deployments and easy searching at a later date. Decreased site load time by implementing gzip of large bundles. Mentorship of junior engineers.

2018-2021

The T-System | Dallas, Texas

Software Engineer

Fullstack development of a web app for ER departments in an Agile environment using TypeScript, AngularJS, Socket.IO, Node.js, Redis, Mongoose, MSSQL, CosmosDB, AKS, Mocha, and Chai. Implemented new HL7 integration workflows in Mirth Connect. Ran security audits to maintain SOC 2 Type 2 compliance. Implemented and updated Azure resources. Updated adjacent C# and .NET APIs using Visual Studio, Git, and SVN as needed. Mentored and taught JS, Git, and Node.js basics to an adjacent team of two. Created and maintained a style guide for product owners and developers.

2018

Call Box | Dallas, Texas

Junior Developer

Maintained both client-facing and internal CRM tools using Adobe ColdFusion, JavaScript, jQuery, and SQL.